

Achievements

Achievement

Arctic Code Vault
Contributor I am
contributed code to the
2020 GitHub Archive
Program

Personal information

Name

Lasitha Dilshan Thilakarathna

Fmail

dilshantilakaratne29@gmail.com

Phone Number

+9477 313 0036

Github

https://github.com/lasithadilshan

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lasitha- | thilakarathna-3027ab120/

References

Jeewaka Nuwan Fernando

Associate Architect - Virtusa +9477 220 0943 jeevakanuwan@gmail.com

Nirodha Rupasinghe

CEO - Java Institute +9471 335 3228 nirodha@javainstitute.edu.lk

LASITHA DILSHAN THILAKARATHNA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Objective

I am a Software Engineer with 4 years of working experience in IT Industry. I am looking for opportunities in career growth and stability and look forward to work with confidence in a dynamic and challenging environment, which utilize my knowledge for the benefits of your organization and enhance my skills as well.

Experience

2022 - Present

Virtusa

Associate Software Engineer, Colombo Perform Frontend, Backend and Data Engineering (Generative AI) tasks

2021 - 2022

Surreytech Consulting Sri Lanka

Intern Engineer One year internship - Full Stack

Education

2023 - Present

Msc in Information Technology (Reading)

SLIIT, Sri Lanka

Master of Science in Information Technology

2018 - 2021

B.Eng in Software Engineering

IIC University of Technology (IIC), Cambodi a

Degree(Second Upper) (GPA - 3.56)

Projects

2024 **AI-POWERED CV EXTRACTOR - GENERATIVE AI**

Virtusa

An Al application that extracts information from various CV formats, organizes it into a predefined template, and exports the result as Word or PDF.

Python, Generative Al, OpenAl, LangChain, LLM

2024 SDLC AUTOMATATION - GENERATIVE AI

Msc Final Year Project

Developed a system leveraging Generative AI to enhance the Software Development Life

Cycle by automating the generation of user stories, test cases, and scripts.

Python, Generative Al, OpenAl, LangChain, LLM

https://github.com/lasithadilshan

2024 BRD TO USER STORY GENERATION - GENERATIVE AI

Virtusa - Generative AI Hakathon

Created a solution to transform Business Requirement Documents (BRD) into user stories using Generative AI, streamlining the software development process.

Python, Generative Al, OpenAl, LangChain, LLM

2023 AFTER HOUR TRANSPORT & FOOD MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

Virtusa

Created a solution to manage foods and transport facilities for the employees to work after office hours.

Microsoft Power Apps, Microsoft SharePoint React TypeScript

2022 **PROTECTIVE_OPENTEXT PROGRAM(PRINT_PRO)**

Virtusa Client Project ANGULAR PROJECT

TypeScript, Bootstrap, CSS, Scss, Material UI

2021 **DOCTOR APPOINTMENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM**

Surreytech Consulting Sri Lanka

Angular Project for managing and scheduling doctor appointments of patients

TypeScript, Bootstrap, CSS, Scss, Material UI

2020 **SOCIAL NETWORK ANDROID APPLICATION**

JAVA INSTITUTE 3'RD YEAR PROJECT

ANDROID VIVA PROJECT

Java, SQLite, Firebase, FireStore

2019 **FOOD ORDERING SYSTEM**

Personal Project

A solution for ordering foods Java Native Android, Firebase

2018 SHOE SHOP WEB CART JAVA WEB APPLICATION

JAVA INSTITUTE 2'ND YEAR PROJECT

JAVA WEB APPLICATION

Java, MySQL

2017 **PHONE SHOP JAVA DESKTOP APPLICATION.**

JAVA INSTITUTE 1'ST YEAR PROJECT

JAVA SE APPLICATION

Java, MySql

Skills

Programming Languages

Java Javascript CSS Html SCSS

Oper Lang LLM

Open Al
LangChain
LLM
Hugging Face
FastAPI

Web Development

Java Spring Boot Angular React





Version control

Github GitLab



API Management

Spring Boot Fast API

Database



Mobile Development

Native Android Google Play Store



Competences

- Career Essentials in Generative Al Microsoft and LinkedIn, 2023
- ✓ **Gen Al Hackathon Certificate of Participation** Virtusa, 2024
- ✓ Virtusa Custom Generative AI Pathway Certification Virtusa, 2024
- ✓ Virtusa Certified GenAl Assisted Engineer Program Certificate Virtusa, 2024